criticalmention.com 2014-05-21

# Privacy Policy | Critical Mention - Media Monitoring

### Critical Mention’s commitment to maintaining your privacy

At Critical Mention we take your privacy seriously and we are committed to protecting the personal information that you choose to share with us. This information is gathered at registration, during your use of the service or otherwise in oral and written communications. We understand the importance of maintaining your trust and confidence in Critical Mention and we shall ensure that the personal information you submit to us remains private, and is used solely for the purposes set out in this policy.

### Information about users generally

Critical Mention gathers information about all our users collectively, such as what area users visit most frequently and what information users access the most. We use this data anonymously in connection with the royalties payable to our content licensors. This information also helps us determine what is most beneficial for our users, and how we can continually create a better overall service for you. We may share this anonymous information with our business partners but only in the aggregate, so that they too may understand how Critical Mention customers use our services. This aggregate information is never shared so that individual users or subscribers can be personally identified and it does not involve the transfer of any personal data we hold about you.

### Information about users specifically

When you register to use this Critical Mention service we require certain personal information about you, such as your name, address, e-mail address and telephone number. This information may also be submitted to Critical Mention in written form or via the telephone. In addition to tracking individual usage and marketing as described below, Critical Mention uses this personal information in several ways:

  * to enable Critical Mention to process, validate and verify subscriptions
  * to deliver the appropriate Critical Mention service to you
  * to assess and improve our services to you and to keep you informed about updates
  * to advise you on your use of the Critical Mention services
  * to invoice and collect payment from individual subscribers

### Tracking Individual Usage

In certain circumstances, your usage of this Critical Mention service and the information that you have retrieved may be reported to your employer or the subscriber who pays for you to access the service. You were notified of this at registration and/or before your first use of the service. In such cases, this personal usage data will only be transferred to the subscribing party that pays for your access to this service. This is done to provide the subscriber with information as to how the service is being used within its organization and for its internal billing and costing purposes.

### Marketing of other Critical Mention Services

If you give us permission, we may use your personal information to make you aware of additional Critical Mention services that may be of interest to you. We may also ask you for additional information, to be provided at your discretion, in an effort to deliver to you the best possible service experience. Critical Mention provides you with the opportunity to opt-in to these types of communications. If you choose to receive these types of communications at the time of registration, but later decide you no longer want to receive them, simply select the Preferences area and under General Registration select the opt-out box.

### Storage of your Personal Information by Critical Mention

The personal information that you provide to Critical Mention is held on our secure servers. We retain this information for so long as you are registered with us and for a reasonable period thereafter to close your account. This information will be shared within the Critical Mention group of companies only. Except as described above, we will not knowingly disclose any of this personal data or information about use of the Critical Mention services to outside parties (other than our sub-contractors if required), except when you expressly consent or we believe the law requires it.

### Updating Account Information

You have the right to ask Critical Mention at any time for a copy of your personal information that we hold. This information shall be provided on payment of an administration fee. Critical Mention allows you to change or correct your personal information at any time. To do so, simply select the Preferences area, and under General Registration and you will find opportunity for editing the information you have submitted. Alternatively you can write to us at the appropriate address specified below.

### Cookies

To enhance your experience of the Critical Mention services, we use a feature on your internet browser called a “cookie.” Cookies are small files that your web browser places on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies for remembering user names and passwords and preferences, tracking click-streams, and for load balancing. Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster service, update results, and provide a more personalized site experience. In order for the services to work, you cannot set up your browser to reject cookies.

### Feedback

Critical Mention provides, within some services, various opportunities for you to submit feedback. Any feedback that is submitted becomes the property of Critical Mention. We may use this feedback, such as success stories, for marketing purposes, or to contact you for further information.

### Privacy Commitment Changes

If Critical Mention decides to change its privacy policy for the Critical Mention services, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather and how we might use that information. If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about Critical Mention’s privacy commitment, please feel free to email us at [legal@criticalmention.com](mailto:legal@criticalmention.com).
